Guide to the Fondren Library Planning Committee records, 1993-1999 UA 210
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Fondren Library Planning Committee records
1993-1999
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 210
0.5 Linear Feet 1 box
Records reflecting the business of the Fondren Library Planning Committee, which explored and planned a redesign of the library at Rice University, 1993-1999.
Biographical / Historical
The Fondren Library was originally built in 1949, designed by Staub & Rather, with William Ward Watkin as consulting architect. In 1968, an addition known as the Graduate Research Addition was built, designed by Staub, Rather & Howze. The Fondren Library Planning Committee's work during 1993-1999 began the process of the internal redesign which took place in 2006, in partnership with the firm of Shepley Bulfinch, and opened a new West entrance to the building, among other changes.
Scope and Contents
Records reflecting the business of the Fondren Library Planning Committee, which explored and planned a redesign of the library at Rice University, 1993-1999. Documents include background readings, consultants' reports, the committee's own reports, development strategy, and versions of plans.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred to the archives after 2000.
Index Terms
Subjects
Architecture; Libraries; Academic libraries -- Texas; Universities and colleges
Document Types
reports; letters (correspondence); drawings (visual works)
- Series I: Background and proposals
  - Background reference, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Proposals, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Development strategy, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Library statistics, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cost analysis, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Description of archives program at Fondren (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II: Reports and correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Library report, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Committee expectations, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Library report, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fondren Library Strategic Plan overview, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Library report, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Consultant reports, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Library report, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Master plan - draft and final versions, Shepley Bulfinch,1999 (Box 1)